Guide to the Sula Benet Papers RISM.RG.2
New York University Archives
Sula Benet Papers
1954-1984
1970-1982
New York University Archives
Benet, Sula, 1903-1982
RISM.RG.2
25 Linear Feet
Dr. Benet, Professor Emerita of Anthropology at Hunter College and senior research associate at RISM, was a colleague of Dr. Rubin and Dr. Margaret Mead for many years. Her papers include correspondence, teaching papers, longevity and aging studies conducted between 1970 and 1973. Also included are reel-to-reel tapes, genealogy charts, questionnaires, surveys and 35 mm color slides possibly used for public lectures.
Related Collections
Vera D. Rubin Papers, RISM RG 1 (located at the Reed Foundation)
Arrangement
The Sula Benet Papers have been organized into two series:
Series I. Personal Papers, has been arranged in four subseries, and
Series II. Professional Papers, is further organized into twelve subseries.
Biographical Note
Sula Benet, Ph.D., was born and educated in Warsaw, Poland. She attended the University of Warsaw where she met her husband, Samuel Benet, a law student. She graduated in 1935 with a graduate degree in ethnography and archaeology. A year later, her dissertation, Hashish in Folk Customs and Beliefs, was published by the Warsaw Society of Sciences. With the help of her mentor, Professor Poniatowski, she was also granted a scholarship for post-doctoral studies. Following her husband's untimely death, she pursued post-graduate studies in anthropology at Columbia University in New York City. She received her Ph.D. in 1944.
Dr. Benet's early professional career included work as a research associate with Dr. Ruth Benedict for the Columbia University Research Project on Contemporary Culture. She subsequently held teaching positions at Columbia University, Fairleigh Dickinson University, and Pratt Institute. When she retired from teaching in 1973, Dr. Benet was a Professor Emeritus at Hunter College of the City University of New York. She then became a Senior Resarch Fellow at the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM), New York City.
She authored numerous books (see bibliography) and served as a consultant on Eastern Europe for the State Department during World War II as well as on numerous gerontological committees.
In 1970, at the invitation of the USSR Academy of Sciences, she began extensive field studies in the Caucasian region of Abkhasia, Russia. Her goal was to investigate Abkhasian lifeways after 50 years of collectivization. Over the next few years, Dr. Benet's study generated numerous publications, including How to Live to be 100, considered a landmark publication on gerontological research.
Fluent in Russian, Polish and Ukrainan, Dr. Benet's areas of specialization included cultural anthropology among the Slavic cultures of Eastern Europe where she conducted field work, sponsored by Columbia University, the Social Science Research Council, RISM, and the Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research. Dr. Benet also conducted studies in culture and personality and aging and longevity.
Based on her research in Russia, Dr. Vera Rubin, director of RISM, proposed that Dr. Benet undertake a major study of the long-living people who had been her chief Abkhasian subjects. Dr. Benet's study led to the development of a US-USSR multidisciplinary research project on longevity, which involved Soviet and American social scientists. The study was known as the Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Aging and Longevity Study (or The Longevity Study).
In 1981, Dr. Benet began editing the English version of a major Soviet publication, The Peoples of the Soviet Union. She died on November 12, 1982, prior to completing the project.
Sources:
Dr. Vera D. Rubin, Obituary of Dr. Sula Benet, Anthropology Newsletter, published by American Anthropologist Association, p. 3
Walter H. Waggoner, Obituary of Sula Benet, New York Times, November 13, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
Some restrictions may apply to the materials in this collection. Please contact the University Archivist for details.
Selected Bibliography
"Le Chanvre dans les Croyances et las Coutumes Populaires," Comptas Rendus das Seances de la Societe des Sciences et des Lettres de Varsovia, XXVII (1934), Classe II, pp. 51-55.
"The Holiday of Chanuka," Our Tribune, Dec. 1940.
"Some Central European Food Patterns in their Relationship to Wartime Problems in Food and Nutrition," with Natalie Jaffe, Comittee on Food Habits, National Research Council, 1943.
"Why They Live to be 100 or Even Older in Abkhasia," New York Times Magazine, December 26, 1972.
Konopie W Wierzenlach I Zwyczahach Ludowych (Hashish in folk customs and beliefs). Warsaw, Poland: Warsaw Society of Sciences, 1936.
Song, Dance and Customs of Peasant Poland. New York: Roy Publishers, 1951.
Patterns of Thought and Behavior in the Culture of Poland. Office of Naval Research, Columbia University, 1952.
The American Riddle Book in collaboration with Carl Withers (James West). New York: Abelard Schuman, 1954.
Riddles of Many Lands in collaboration with Carl Withers. New York: Abelard Schuman, 1954. Reprinted 1961, 1967 by E.M. Hale & Co., Eau Claire, Wisconsin.
Festival Menus Around The World. New York: Abelard Schuman, 1956; Revised edition 1970.
The Village of Viriatino. New York: Doubleday & Co., 1970. Trans., edited (with an introduction), and annotated from the original Russian into English.
Abkhasia: The Long Living People of the Caucasus, 1972
Proceedings.; Pamphlets.; Charts (graphic documents); Epidemiology.; Aging |z Russian S.F.S.R.; Aging -- United States.; Culture.; Education.; Cultural relations.; Articles.; Demography.; Ethnology.; Education, Higher -- United States.; Traditional medicine.; Questionnaires.; Notes.; Research Institute for the Study of Man; Rubin, Vera D.
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1954-1984, undated
  - Subseries A: Biographical and Personal Papers, 1982-1984, undated; 0.5 Linear Feet; no content
    - Brief Biography of Sula Benet, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Curriculum Vitae (revised), circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Medical questionnaire [Russian], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Last Will and Testament of Sula Benet, 1982 Aug (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Papers associated with Sula Benet memorial, list of attendees, notes, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Memorial program containing eulogy notes by Vera Rubin, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Memorial programs, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Letters of tribute, sympathy cards read at Sula Benet Memorial, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Corespondence, obituary, New York Times, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Obituary, American Anthropology Association, 1982 November-December (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Notice of Probate, memorandum, 1982 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Memorandum re Sula Benet Will, 1983 January (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, legal forms, notes, 1983 May (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, legal forms, 1983 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, draft material and notes for Sula Benet biography, 1984 July-October (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Draft list of published books, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Draft list of S. Benet books, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Personal stationery [blank], undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hunter College stationery [blank], undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Reseach Institute for the Study of Man stationery [blank], undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Personal note cards [blank], undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Unicef note cards [blank], undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Who's Who, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Subseries B: Personal Correspondence, 1954-1982, undated
    Scope and Content
    .5 linear feet (1 box), arranged chronologically.
    - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Unorganized, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Greeting Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Subseries C: Journals and Notebooks, undated
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  - Subseries D: Ephemera-Postcards, Brochures, Stamps
    - Various Postcards, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Unknown Postard Collection, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Museum Berlin [postcard collection], undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Muzium Wsi Opolski, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lenin Memorial [postcard collection], undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - The Itinerant Painter, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Georgian Folk Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Playbills, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Catalog, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Georgia Russia [travel guides], undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Tbilisi University, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - In Tourist Guide USSR, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Various Travel guides, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Stamps, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series II: Professional Papers
  - Subseries A: General Correspondence, 1971-1982, undated
    - 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 60 Minutes, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Media, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Associated Press: "Our Elders: A Generation Neglected", undated; "Our Elders: A Generation Neglected" (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Subseries B: Columbia University Research Project on Contemporary Culture
    - Poland 1 of 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Poland 2 of 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Denmark, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Spain, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Turkey, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Italy, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Portugal, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Yugoslavia, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Maps, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Partial/Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Partial/Draft Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Ruth Benedict Lecture, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Article Mead, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Geoffrey Gorer Article, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Essay Margaret Mead, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Mead Article, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Tracking Papers/Misc., undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Culture and Personality, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Czecholovakia, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Albania, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - India, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Norway, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - China, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - England, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Irish, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Yuasa, Hachiro, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Alphonse Riesenfeld, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Robert Hackenberg-Fundementals of Genealogical Method, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Juliana Field, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Jews, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Social Structures, Radcliffe-Brown, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Genetics-Dobzhansky, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Erik Erikson-Zones and Modes of the Psycho-Sexual Development of the Child, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Soviet Union, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Mental Health, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The Maya, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Basque Studies, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Religion, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Sweden, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Felix Gross, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Gorer, Geoffrey, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Florence Keuckhohm-Dominant and Substitute Profiles of Culture Stratification, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Kluchhohn-Branches of Anthropology, Patterning as exemplified in Navaho Culture, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Ralph Linton, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-44)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-24)
  - Subseries C: Conference Papers
    - Conferenece Papers, 1964-1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 8, Folder 2-14)
  - Subseries D: Teaching Papers, Hunter College
    - Duffy-Irish Folklore, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 8, Folder 16-31)
    - Teaching Papers/Misc., undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Culture and Personality, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Culture and Personality/Student Papers, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Culture and Education, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Dynamics of Culture, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Intercultural Relations, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Notes Related to Teaching, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Letters of Recommendation, 1969-1970, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Culture and Personality, 1938-1945, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Human Nature, 1949-1972 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Wolfenstein-A Theory of Punishment, Jan, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Teenage Culture, 1948-1969 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - A Neurosis is Just a Bad Habit, June 1967 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Urban-Rural Migration, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Outlines, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Discipline, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Subseries E: Published Writings
    - Subsubseries I: "How to Live to be 100"
      - Book Cover, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Book Excerpt, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Unnamed, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Speaking Engagements, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Book Reviews, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Unnamed, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Media Events, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Misc. Papers, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - News Hunter (in which Benet is featured), undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Beliefs and Customs of Hemp, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Life and Stars For Long Lived People in Psychology for Doctors, 1977 August (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - New York Times Article, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Folklore, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - The Village of Viriatine Cover, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Publishing/European Profiles, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Unnamed, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Book Reviews, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Subsubseries II: Manual for Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Aging and Longevity, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Working Draft of Manual for Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Aging and Longevity, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Manual for Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Aging and Longevity, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Subsubseries III: Correspondence Regarding
      - 1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 1971 January (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 1971 February (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 1971 December (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 1972 January (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 1972 February (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 1972 March-April (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 1972 May-June (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - 1972 July-August (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - 1972 September-October (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - 1972 November-December (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - 1973 January-March (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - 1973 April-June (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - 1973 July-September (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - 1973 October-December (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - 1974 January-March (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - 1975 January-March (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - 1975 July-September (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - 1975 October-December (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - 1976 January-March (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - 1976 July-September (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - 1976 October-December (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - 1977 January-March (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - 1979 January (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - 1981 October-December (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - 1982 January (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - Unnamed, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Subsubseries IV: Foreign Languages
      - Unnamed, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-35)
      - Archaeology /Ukranian Academy of Science, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - The Present Course of Burzhyasian Ethnography, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - "Current State of Olmec Problems (reprint from Soviet Ethnography 2), 1962 (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - "Structure of Society and its Modifications" (reprint "Modern & Recent History), 1969 (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Several Questions on the Development of the American Nations (reprint from Soviet Ethnography phy. 4), 1968 (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - Village of Duripsh (a historicoethnographic study of collective farms in Abkhasia), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Tensions in the French-Canadian Question (reprint from "From Alaska to Tierra del Fuego" in History of Ethnography of AMerican Countries), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 42)
      - Longevity, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Subseries F: Longevity Studies Done By Others
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
    - Jewish Population-USSR, circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hunza, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Field Work, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Take to Russia, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Dirth, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Aggression, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - The Abnormal, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Culture Change, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Moral Training, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Poverty and Social Change, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Race and Culture, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Caucus-General, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Human Biology, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Dunn: The Great Russian Peasant..., undated (Box 12, Folder 20-21)
    - Theory and Method in Cross-Cultural Psychology, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Expenditures-Receipts, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Cutlure and Personality, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - SB Questionaire, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Reviews and Publicity on "How to Live to 100", undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Stress, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Network Analysis, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Jews-Causcus [empty], undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Social Structure [empty, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Review by Soviet [empty], undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Khtat Prologue General Stat... [empty], undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Physical Types, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Hungary [empty], undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Hospitality Entertainment, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Friendship [empty], undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Bibliographies: Longevity, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Recep., undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Medical History Questionnaire, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Health Hazard Appraisal and Census Questionaire, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Family History Questionnaires, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Women, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Work, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Life History, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Questionnaire, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Daily Events-Form A, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Dietary Questionnaires (DHEW), undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - USSR Political, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Miscellanous: Aging, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Articles on USSR, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Age verification, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Gene Map of Human Chromosome (Victor McKusick and F. Ruddle), undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Unnamed, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Aging and Children, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Aging Jews, 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - The influence of extraversion and neuroticism on subjective well-being: happy and unhappy people, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Howells, W.W. Universality and Variation in Human Nature, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Benedict, Ruth "Childe Rearing in Certain European Countries", 1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Language and Culture, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Some Aspects of Psychology of the People of Great Russia, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - France, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Culture Area, Clark Wissler, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Personality Aggression, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - M. M. National Character, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Japan, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Paleolithic Art-Sula Benet, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Abkhasia-Diet, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Adzharia [empty], undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Armenia [empty], undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Dagestan [empty], undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Georgia [empty], undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Longevity-Siberia [empty], undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Polish Village Outline, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Ukranian Village, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Peoples of the Soviet Union, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - The role of the Ages in Prim. Society, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Union, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Sula Benet and Lucy Jarvis NBC (photograph), undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Medical Questionnaires (Dr. Arnold Schecter), undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Long-Lived Caucus, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence-Ford and U.S. Government Agencies, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Sula Benet Soviet Study, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Final Report to Ford Foundation, 1974 January 1 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Biography, Etc..., undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - List of Family Dates Missing, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Data-Cementaries, town clerk reports, etc..., undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Spurling Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Hadlock Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Fernald Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Gilley Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Stanley Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Bunker, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Questionnaire #1 Original and Extra Copies, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Questionnaire, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Photographs without interviews, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - List of Informants, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Original Interviews (Filed by Number), undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Central and Western European Studies, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Joel Halpern-The Ladruga-A Century of Change, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Duchogors, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Ruth Benedict, undated (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 18, Folder 3-7)
    - Longevity Studies Done By Others, 1969-1980 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
    - Questions Regarding The Treatment of Aged, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Retirement, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Political Consequences of Aging, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Values-Men and Women, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Psychology of Aging, 1972-1975 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Sexuality in Aging, 1972-1976 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Services for the Aged, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Demography, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Death, 1973-1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Centenarians, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - The Young and the Old, 1966-1976 (Box 20, Folder 11)